bam.org 2014-12-17

# BAM | Privacy Policy

Effective: Nov 10, 2010

The Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM) is committed to protecting your privacy. This policy describes the personal information we collect about you, the security measures we take to protect your information, the ways we use your information, and the limited situations in which we may share your information with third parties. Our policy also describes the choices you can make about how we collect and use your information. We encourage you to read the complete privacy policy; use of BAM's family of websites (e.g., BAM.org and BAMNextStage.org) constitutes your acceptance of this policy. 

A. Information you give us  
BAM will often request information that personally identifies you (personal information) or allows us to contact you. Generally, this information is requested when you purchase tickets, make donations to BAM, register for email newsletters or alerts, participate in a promotion or an online survey, contact us with a question or suggestion, request postal mailings, or apply for employment. Personal information collected by BAM generally includes a home address, email address, phone number, credit card information including expiration date and billing address, and product or genre preferences; it may include other information as needed to provide a specific service you requested or as part of an online survey or promotion. We collect this information when you enter it on BAM websites or provide it voluntarily. You may remain anonymous to us if you choose to pay by cash in person at the Box Office.

B. Automatic information  
When you visit BAM's websites, we automatically collect website usage information, as well as information about your computer and Internet connection. This includes your computer's IP address, the type and version of browser and operating system you use, your Internet domain, and if you visit via a link from another website, the URL of the linking page. This site visitation data is identified only by a unique ID number, and it is not linked with personal information unless you choose to log in. We aggregate this usage information and use it only to identify the levels and areas of interest in BAM and to improve and refine our websites, services, and security. We may perform (or have third parties perform) analyses of visitors' behavior, and may share aggregated, anonymous data with funders, sponsors, or agencies.

We use cookie technology to gain information that helps us improve the user experience and enhances the functionality of our websites. A cookie is a small amount of data sent by our websites and stored on your computer's hard drive that our site can read, and which helps us keep track of how you use our websites. Many web browsers automatically accept cookies by default but contain an option for you to disable the cookie acceptance if you prefer. If you disable cookie acceptance, bear in mind that you will not be able to purchase tickets to BAM online. We do not allow unrelated third parties to set cookies via BAM's family of websites.

BAM uses electronic images known as web beacons to monitor the activity of our email messages. These web beacons allow BAM's email service provider to obtain information such as the IP address of the computer that opened the email and what links were clicked within the email. With both cookies and web beacon technology, the information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. 

BAM uses remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online. This means that BAM allows third party vendors to show BAM’s ads on sites across the Internet. BAM and these third party vendors use first party cookies and third party cookies together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on a visitor’s past visits to BAM.org.

We employ third parties to perform functions like sending postal mail and email, removing repetitive information from customer lists, and processing credit card payments. These parties have access to personal information that is necessary to perform their functions, but they are contractually obligated not to use it for other purposes. 

BAM employs the latest safeguards and technologies to protect your information:

Secure Web Servers  
BAM employs secure web servers hosted in a  [SAS 70 Type II](http://sas70.com/sas70_overview.html) and  [SysTrust](https://cert.webtrust.org/ntta_systrust.html) certified data center. A  [Network Solutions](http://www.networksolutions.com/SSL-certificates/index.jsp) SSL (Secure Socket Layer) certificate is used for the secure encrypted exchange of data between your web browser and BAM.org using up to 128bit SSL encryption. Network Solutions Digital Certificates are trusted by over 99% of all browsers, applications, servers, and clients, including: Microsoft® Internet Explorer 5.01 +, Mozilla® Firefox 1.0+, Mozilla® 0.6+, Google® Chrome, Konqueror (KDE), Opera 7.0+, Apple® Safari 1.2 +, Camino 1.0+, and AOL® 5+. 

Credit Card Processing  
Our transactional website is Payment Card Industry (PCI), certified by  [SecurityMetrics](https://www.securitymetrics.com/sitecertinfo.adp), which verifies that merchant credit card handling processes are in compliance with Payment Card Industry (PCI) Data Security Standards. Once BAM has received all required information from you via a web browser, the transaction is processed with your bank via a secure encrypted Internet connection. Our web servers do not retain any credit card numbers, but we do process your credit card information through a secure internal database. 

Firewall  
BAM.org has redundant, dedicated firewalls that protect both its transactional system and the data passing through it.

We use your personal information for the following purposes: 

-To improve site functionality, relevance, and security 

-To deliver personalized services such as e-newsletters and postal mailings 

-To help us create and publish content most relevant to you

-To allow you access to a personalized ticketing service area 

-To support strategic development

Occasionally, BAM may make some personal information available to select third party organizations, including but not limited to: nonprofit arts organizations, affiliated organizations, and companies or organizations with whom we have a contractual or sponsor relationship. This information generally consists of your name and mailing address. We do not share your email address or telephone number. You can request at anytime that we do not share your name and address with such third parties. 

Performances at BAM are often produced or presented by other organizations. When you make a purchase for a performance presented or produced by one of these organizations, BAM may provide them with information regarding your purchase. This information may include, but shall not be limited to, your name, address, telephone number, and email address, as well as general details of your purchase, which may include, but shall not be limited to, the date of your purchase, any offer you responded to, and the dollar amount of your transaction. 

BAM may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on BAM or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of BAM and its family of websites; or (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of BAM employees, users of BAM products or services, or members of the public. 

If you would like us not to share your information as described above, please email us at info@BAM.org or call us at 718.636.4100 (press 1). BAM will not share your information without your permission, other than for the limited exceptions already listed. 

BAM's family of websites are for a general audience. We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children. 

Our websites may include links to other websites or embedded content such as YouTube videos. We do not control the privacy policies of the destination sites. Once you leave our servers or watch a YouTube video (you can see where you are by checking the URL in the location bar on your browser), use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you are visiting. 

BAM will occasionally update this privacy statement. When we do, we will revise the date at the bottom of the privacy statement. 

BAM welcomes your comments regarding this privacy statement. Please email info@BAM.org, call 718.636.4100 (press 1), or write to us at: Ticket Services, 30 Lafayette Avenue, Brooklyn, NY 11217. 

Effective: Nov 10, 2010
